Guide to the New York City 100 Records 1995-2000 (Bulk 1997-1999) MS 444
New-York Historical Society
- Series IX: Program Roster, 1999, 1999-2000 (Box 17, Box 6, Volume BV, Box 7)
  - Subseries 3: New York City 100 Pop-Up Book, 1999-2000, undated (Volume BV, Box 17, Box 7, Box 6)
    - a. Press Release, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - b. Correspondence, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - c. Invitation to Book Launch Party, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - d. Advertising and Promotion, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - e. Press Clippings, 1999-2000 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - f. Original Manuscripts, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - g. New York Pop-Up Book, 1999 (Volume 1)
    - h. Color and Black and White "Blues" or Printer's Proofs, 1999 (Volume 2)
    - h. Color and Black and White "Blues" or Printer's Proofs, 1999 (Volume 3)
    - i. Hirschfeld Drawing of Guys and Dolls, Negatives, Undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - j. Artwork Proofs for Pop-up Book, Undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Series X: Educational Outreach, 1998-2001 (Box 7)
  A collaboration of The New-York Historical Society and The New York Board of Education, with the assistance of many contributors, produced two resource manuals for New York City school teachers, one in 1998 and one in 2000. The first (Box 7, Folder 3) provides students from elementary through high school with New York City historical content to complement their social studies and history curricula, focusing on the development of research skills. The second (Box 7, Folder 5) contains maps, charts and tables, time lines, photographs and a wealth of primary and secondary sources to be used by teachers of all grades. Its primary subject is immigration and it is subdivided into segments such as "Leaving Home", " The Journey", "Preserving Cultural Identity", "Assimilation", and "Next Generations." In addition to copies of the manuals, this series contains correspondence (Box 7, Folder 4) that includes thank you letters from both the Mayor and the Deputy Mayor.
  - a. New York City 100 Teachers' Resource Manual, September 1998 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - b. Letters of Congratulation, 1998-2001 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - c. America Begins in New York, The Peopling of New York: A Teachers' Resource Manual on Immigration, June 2000 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Series XI: Centennial Sponsors and Media Partnerships, 1997-1999 (Box 8, Box 7, Box 9)
  Series XI is focused on the sponsors and partnerships that supported New York City 100. Included are correspondence, facsimiles, proposals, invitations, lists of potential and actual event participants, invoices and copies of checks. Some of the folders contain items related to a single partner, others to a single event. From Box 8, Folder 7 through Box 9, Folder 3 are the contents of the organization's Fundraising Binders. Arranged alphabetically by organization or individual, the folders contain correspondence, telephone messages, handwritten notes, newspaper clippings, donation information and ledger sheets.
  - a. New York Times Breakfast May 13, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - b. Thirteen-WNET, $150,000, May 20, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - c. Gracie Mansion, "Save the Date" Letter for Potential Funders, August 15, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - d. Committee for 100 Solicitation Package, September 1997 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - e. Real Estate Board Solicitation, October 16, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - f. AT&T Foundation Office Proposal, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - g. Target, Various Other Proposals, 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - h. Wall Street Breakfast with Mayor Giuliani, April 15, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - i. Rudin Loan / Reconciliation, 1998-1999 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - j. 1999 Fund-Raising, 1998-1999 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - k. CHASE Reports / Correspondence, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - l. Final Correspondence, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - m. Fundraising Binders (1 of 6 A-Z), 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - m. Fundraising Binders (2 of 6 C-E), 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - m. Fundraising Binders (3 of 6 F-J), 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - m. Fundraising Binders (4 of 6 K-Q), 1997-1998 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - m. Fundraising Binders (5 of 6 R-T), 1997-1998 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - m. Fundraising Binders (6 of 6 U-Z), 1997-1998 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Series XII: Public Relations and Advertising, 1998-1999, 1997-1999, undated (Box 9, Box 17, Box 10)
  This series contains materials related to advertising and public relations. Among the items are correspondence, contracts, samples of web page design and copies of advertisements and other final products (e.g. cover art for the 1998-99 Green Book in Box 9, Folder 9).
  - a. Media Partners Office Files (1 of 5), 1998 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - a. Media Partners Office Files (2 of 5, The New York Times), 1997-1999 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - a. Media Partners Office Files (3 of 5 Daily News), 1998 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - a. Media Partners Office Files (4 of 5 City Guide), 1998 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - a. Media Partners Office Files (5 of 5 NY1), 1997-1998 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - b. Green Book Cover Art, 1998-1999 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - c. New York Convention and Visitor's Bureau, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - d. Web Site: Working Folder, 1997-1999 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - e. City Guide Ads, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - f. Time Out New York Ads, 1998-1999 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - g. Pentagram Banner Design with Casting Choices, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - h. Daily News Ads (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - i. The New York Times Ads, 1998-1999 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - [j. Public Relations], 1997-1998 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - [k. "NY1 Minutes" Video Cassette], Undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Series XIII: Products/Licensing, 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  The New York City 100 licensed several products to generate revenue. This series contains materials relating to scarves created by Nicole Miller and dolls marketed by the Home Shopping Network. Items include correspondence, design elements, photographs and documentation of the request for trademark extension (Box 10, Folder 4). Folder c. Nicole Miller Scarves was removed from the series and its contents were transferred to the N-YHS museum collection.
  - a. Nicole Miller Design File, 1997-1998 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - b. Home Shopping Network Correspondence, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Series XIV: Accounting and Finance [restricted for 75 years], 1997-2000 (Box 13, Box 10, Box 12, Box 11)
  Accounting and financial materials have been maintained in their original order, with each subseries reflecting the contents of a binder or box. The records range from budgets to tax returns, and include such documents as invoices, copies of cancelled checks, deposit slips, expense reports, and bank statements. Other materials include correspondence, copies of agreements and royalty statements.
  Access Restrictions
  Series XIV: Accounting and Finance is restricted from use for 75 years, or until 2085.
  - Subseries 1: "New York City 100 Chart of Accounts" Binder [restricted for 75 years], 1997-1998 (Box 10, Box 11)
    Scope and Content Note
    Consisting primarily of invoices, expense reports and spreadsheets, this subseries is organized by account. Most of the major sections are preceded by summary sheets. There are many item duplicates. The contents of Box 10, Folder 6 focus on contributions. There are lists of contributors, correspondence and copies of checks, as well as internal memoranda and transmittals. Box 11, Folder 6 represents items that were not filed within the binder tabs, but were loose or contained in the binder pocket. Among this group are a Skyline Corporate Voucher Agreement, invoice logs, a handwritten ledger book and a number of receipts.
    - Support & Revenue [restricted for 75 years], 1997-1998 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Expenses: Supplies 211 and Catering 212 [restricted for 75 years], 1997-1998 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Expenses: Equip 231, Printing 261 and Eq Rent 281 [restricted for 75 years], 1997-1998 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Expenses: Consulting 311 [restricted for 75 years], 1997-1998 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Expenses: Fare & Food 331 [restricted for 75 years], 1997-1998 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Expenses: Tel. Com. 811 and Mail & Messr 821 [restricted for 75 years], 1997-1998 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Expenses: Advertising 411 and Other Accounts – 812, 900, 531, 253, 261, 551, 451, 341 [restricted for 75 years], 1997-1998 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Expenses: Temp/Prof 114 [restricted for 75 years], 1998 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Expenses: Furniture and Gracie Mansion [restricted for 75 years], 1997 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - "New York City 100 Chart of Accounts" Binder Loose Materials [restricted for 75 years], 1997-1998 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 2: "New York City 100 Acct # 1229900" Binder [restricted for 75 years], 1998-1999 (Box 11)
    The binder represented by this subseries is divided into categories and contains copies of New-York Historical Society financial documents concerning invoices paid. Examples of the categories are Advertising, Consultants, Equipment Lease, Printing, Supplies and Website. Within Box 11, Folder 8 are two copies of an invoice from the CPA firm – Berson & Corrado –responsible for the New York City 100's accounting and tax services. These invoices were not filed within any category, but were loosely contained in the binder.
    - Categories A - M [restricted for 75 years], 1998-1999 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Categories P – W [restricted for 75 years], 1998-1999 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 3: "PAYCHEX" Binder [restricted for 75 years], 1999 (Box 11)
    Payroll information for two employees of the New York City 100 – Marie Salerno and Natasha Caba – is contained within this subseries. Invoices and correspondence related to payroll processing by the company Paychex, Inc. are also included. A variety of computer generated printouts such as Payroll Journal, Department Summary, Time Sheet, Deposit Report and Employee Earnings Record are among those contained in Box 11, Folder 9. The materials in this subseries all fall within the mid- to late 1999 time frame.
    - PAYCHEX – Printouts and Correspondence 7/99-12/99 [restricted for 75 years], 1999 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - PAYCHEX – Quarterly Reports 2nd and 3rd 1999 [restricted for 75 years] (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - PAYCHEX – IRS and NYS Dept. Of Labor Materials [restricted for 75 years], 1999 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 4: Expense Activity Binder [restricted for 75 years], 1997-1999 (Box 12)
    Contained within a large black binder were bills, statements, invoices, copies of checks, correspondence and other items related primarily to New York City 100 expenses. Subseries 4 includes these documents. Most of the material is arranged alphabetically by the name of the vendor or individual paid. There are, in addition, two sections labeled "Expenses", which contains original expense reports, and "Chase CD's", with statements relating to CD balances (Box 12, Folder 7). Box 12, Folder 8 holds items that were not filed within the binder but contained in its front pocket. One of those items is the organization's Special Event Liability insurance policy.
    The bulk of the items within this subseries are dated 1999 although there are some with 1998 dates and a few, 1997.
    - Expense Activity A - C [restricted for 75 years], 1999-1999 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Expense Activity D - M [restricted for 75 years], 1997-1999 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Expense Activity N – R [restricted for 75 years], 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Expense Activity S (1 of 2) [restricted for 75 years], 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Expense Activity S (2 of 2) [restricted for 75 years], 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Expense Activity T – Z [restricted for 75 years], 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Expense Activity - Expenses and Chase CD's [restricted for 75 years], 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Expense Activity Binder – Loose Materials [restricted for 75 years], 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 5: Miscellaneous Financial Records [restricted for 75 years], 1997-2000 (Box 13)
    This subseries is made up of folders and loose items contained within the New York City 100 "Accounting and Finance" materials (i.e., documents not contained within binders). The folder titles shown below are those assigned by the organization although the contents do not always reflect the folder title. It appears that many of the items had not been filed by the time the organization completed its mission. Many are dated late 1999 and into 2000.
    Within the subseries are a wide variety of document types such as invoices (including 'final' bills), correspondence, bank statements, deposit slips, handwritten ledger sheets, PAYCHEX printouts, copies of checks, expense reports, lists of contributions, general ledger reports, budgets, payment schedules, tax returns, handwritten notes and draft documents. Box 13, Folder 3 contains blank stationary and envelopes.
    - NYC 100 Deposits [restricted for 75 years], 1999-2000 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - New York 100 [restricted for 75 years], 1997-1999 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - NYC 100 Payroll, Taxes, etc. [restricted for 75 years], 1998-2000 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Bank Statements 3/99 – 6/00 [restricted for 75 years], 1999-2000 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Loose Materials re New York Pop-Up Book [restricted for 75 years], 1999-2000 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Loose Materials – Various Documents Types [restricted for 75 years], 1997-2000 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Series XV: Video and Computer Archive, 1997-1999, undated (Box 14, Box 15)
  A number of items were produced by the New York City 100 in video and computer formats. Box 14, Folder 1 contains two FUJI Metal Videocassettes (Betacam): "Pentagram Design Inc. NYC 100 Scan Conversion" (small format) and "NYC 100 Logo" (large format). Box 14, Folder 2 holds three videocassettes: "Women to Women: NYC's 100th Birthday"; "New York Close-Up – September 1997"; and "NYC 100 Logo." In Box 15 are seven Macintosh format Zip 100 disks. All are labeled or contain lists of files. The majority of files are images. Some are from the educational curriculum; others from advertisements, logo and letterhead, the New York Pop-Up Book, and various events.
  - FUJI Metal Videocassettes – Betacam, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - VHS Videocassettes, 1997, 1998, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Zip 100 Disks, 1998, 1999 (Box 15, Folder unknown container)
- Series XVI: Press Clippings, 1897-1898, 1997-1998 (Box 18)
  Clippings from New York area publications are included in this series. All fall within the 1997-1998 time frame with the exception of copied New York Times material from 1897-1898. Clippings from New York area publications are included in this series. All fall within the 1997-1998 time frame with the exception of copied New York Times material from 1897-1898.
  - New York Daily News, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - New York Post, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - The New York Times, 1897-1898, 1997-1998 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Time Out Magazine, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Press Clippings from the New York Area, 1997-1998 (Box 18, Folder 5)